Let's pick what we're having for breakfast tomorrow.
Roger!
You don't have to run.
He doesn't listen at all.
Let's see... If it's a cold, you'll need water, a sports drink and dairy products.
Is there anything that's easy to digest...?
Do you want to get something for yourself for breakfast, Rin?
Like cereal?
Daikichi.
Yeah?
Did I spread it?
You...
Cold Germs are all over.
It could be caught by spreading, or it could develop on its own.
You don't have to worry about who spreads it.
Can I also choose a get-well gift?
Of course.
These.
Put them inside the basket.
Oh, Kouki-kun.
Why are you in the snack aisle!?
Kouki! Breakfast is-
I pulled it out!
Oyatsu Fansubs Presents
Usagi
Drop
ashita no koto ha wakannai
明日のことはわかんない。
We don't know what's going to happen tomorrow.
korette gisei toha chigau. nanika ga chigau.
これってギセイとは違う。何かが違う。
This is different from sacrificing. Very different.
batsugeemu jan, nante omowanai.
罰ゲームじゃん、なんて思わない。
I don't think this is a punishment game either.
de, nande nanoka wakannai
で、なんでなのかわかんない。
But I'm not really sure what it is.
chotto shakuzen to shinai kedo,
ちょっと釈然としないけど、
In fact, I do feel quite troubled,
kimi no sonzai, ima daiji da, nantemonjanai.
きみの存在、いま大事だ、なんてもんじゃない。
Your existence is no longer so important anymore.
owaranai koto nante konoyo no dokonimonai.
終わらないことなんてこの世の何処にも無い。
Things that last forever don't exist anywhere in this world.
naku no ha tsurai nja, naino,
泣くのは辛いんじゃ、ないの、
Crying is a very painful thing,
ai no SWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
愛のSWEET DROPS SWEET DROPS
Love's sweet drops, sweet drops.
zutto yume mite itaine.
ずっと夢みていたいネ。
How I wish my dreams could continue on and on.
motto yasashiku shitaine.
もっとやさしくしたいね。
I want to be more gentle.
kimi to iraretara, HAPPY.
きみと居られたら、HAPPY。
Just being together with you, I'm happy.
onnanoko tte tsuyoi ne.
女の子って強いね。
Girls are strong.
dakedo tokidoki yowai ne.
だけどときどき弱いね。
But at times they are weak
bokura no negai ha, HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
ぼくらの希いは、HAPPY HAPPY HAPPY!
Our dream is to be happy, happy, happy!
sonna hibi mo HAPPY.
そんな日々もHAPPY。
Those happy days.
JUST WANNA MAKE YOU HAPPY☆
My house is over here.
It's better if we go home, otherwise we'll disturb her.
OK.
The breakfast for tomorrow is inside. Give it to your mom.
It's heavy.
It's really heavy.
Well then, let's go back home, Rin.
Mom! Daikichi bought us things to eat!
Didn't you hear what I said!?
Hey, Kouki.
Daikichi-san.
I'm really sorry to have you always looking out for us.
Oh no, I should apologise instead.
You're always looking after Rin.
How is Rin-chan doing?
Oh, she's completely recovered.
She started going to school today.
Good evening.
Isn't it great, Rin-chan?
I'm making some of that porridge right now.
I'll get better after eating it.
Rin! Toss the tooth with me.
Come with me, over here.
Be careful, Kouki.
Yes~!
Nitani-san, you could have caught it from when you were looking after Rin.
I'm sorry about it.
I'm going to toss it from here.
I see lots of people every day.
It's so high.
I also take a fully packed train to work, as well.
I'm going to throw it onto the roof.
You never know who you got it from.
So you don't have to worry, it's only a cold.
I understand.
Well, in the very least, please let me help with Kouki-kun.
It's fine even if it's just getting him from school.
Thank you very much.
Rin! We're going home.
Daikichi! Let's play a game.
Sure. We'll play next time.
Kouki, be sure to help out your mother.
OK.
Oh, I almost forgot.
Pudding and that small bottle of drink are from Rin.
Thank you so much, Rin-chan!
I love eating puddings.
Have a good night.
Daikichi! Hurry up!
It's so early. It's Sunday today, you know.
You promised we'll practise for the skipping competition together.
What's the matter?
This one's also starting to move.
Brush it slowly.
Stop touching it.
Ouch!
You don't have to push yourself too hard.
No, I'm already well enough.
I'm really sorry to always have to rely on you for help.
Us too. Thank you for your help.
No, it's nothing.
It's quite unexpected, coming from Kouki.
He's not good at it.
Kouki, you're jumping too soon.
What?
When the rope turns one round, you jump at this point, right?
It won't work if your hands and legs are not working together.
I see.
The hands first, then comes the legs.
Slow down your hands and jump to see.
I got it!
Daikichi! Teach me too! Teach me too!
Sure sure.
Rin, your arms are too far apart.
Close your arms like this.
Daikichi-san~!
You sure are early!
Good mooorning!
They are way too excited.
Nobu-kun is good.
He has a brother, so he learns everything from him.
Are you not skipping, Sayaka-chan?
Her front teeth have fallen off.
The girls have it tough even when they are so young.
Sayaka-chan.
What does your tooth container look like?
Did you get a cute one?
What's that?
It's a case to store teeth inside for commemoration.
You haven't heard of it?
Commemoration?
There's a type that's small and round. They're really cute looking.
Very small?
Very cute?
Yeah, mine is the shape of a butterfly.
What? Seems like something that Rin will really like.
I'm too careless!
I didn't think there would be such a thing.
I'm always like this ever since meeting Rin.
Getting paranoid and anxious over the littlest things.
Kaga Rin
Daikichi
The meat-potato Daikichi
makes are delicious, and
he can run very fast too.
This is for you, Daikichi.
I drew this in school.
Daikichi
It's to introduce a family member.
Well, I guess it's fine.
Wow, it's so cute!
What is this?
You use this to contain your fallen off teeth. It's a form of memory.
Memory?
Thank you! Kouki-kun's mom.
You're welcome.
I can't thank you enough.
But what about Kouki...
It's fine, it's fine.
I'm going to throw them forever!
...That's how it is.
I threw those before onto the roof.
Will that be OK?
Don't worry, it's all right.
You can toss them onto the roof and also keep them as memory. Isn't that pretty good?
You're right.
Rin, I'll also do my best to skip this time round.
What?
Touching your tooth again.
It'll come off even if you don't worry about it.
No matter how you look at it, it seems like she's been punched in the face.
She won't be able to smile for a while.
OK, it's all done.
Let's hurry and go.
You've grown taller again.
What? You're joining in too?
I seem to have gotten fat.
Me too.
It's a pain once we reach this age.
I hope to control it, regardless of which.
Look, Daikichi-san's doing the boxer jump.
Wow, impressive!
The pressure on the knees are smaller if you skip like this.
Really?
Daikichi! Teach me that move!
5, 6, 7, 8, 9, 10, 11...
I'm not showing you!
What's that? You're the only one acting cool.
Perfect your normal skipping before you ask me to teach you that.
What?!
Stop right there!
I want to learn too!
Rin-chan, your backward skipping is really good.
Kids are incredible.
Oh, really?
Kids are always energetic.
Rock, paper, scissors! One more time!
Where do they get all the stamina from?
No, but adults are amazing too.
Adults?
Both of you should also have heard about it somehow.
I'm not Rin's father.
I only started living with Rin about one year ago.
Before that, I used to spend all the time I have on myself.
My life started changing after I started living with Rin.
But all of you have already been with your kids for a long time.
I don't feel anything, since I've been at it for only a short period of time.
So I don't know if I'll be able to bear with not having time for myself from now on.
Hm? I don't have a problem.
Me too.
Me either.
Eh? Really?
Because... right?
Eh? What do you mean?!
Rin, wasn't the skipping tournament today?
Yeah...
Rin?
I failed.
How many jumps?
15 times.
That's bad.
What about the backward skip?
203 times.
What! You can skip that many times?
Could it be, you got first place?
Yeah, this is the certificate.
You really worked hard. Amazing.
But I should be able to do more of the forward skip.
Well, you only get to decide the winner once.
Besides, you were able to jump so many times.
I know for sure.
Oh, I lost weight!
What?
Why you!
Are we there yet?
It'll probably take ten more minutes.
You've got to show them your front teeth.
OK!
I already told you, don't keep touching it.
I'm also going to show them how I can skip.
I see.
You've grown rather tall recently.
My mom and dad will surely be surprised.
Aunty might even say "You're even taller than me"?
I don't think it'll be so soon.
We should also tell Grandpa about it.
Yeah.
I'm back!
Oh, Rin-chan! I've waited so long for you.
I'm home.
Oh look look, you've really grown taller.
Are you taller then your classmates?
Yeah.
I would have drove to pick you two up if only you called earlier.
It's only a ten minute walk here.
Rin is able to walk.
You'll become taller than me very soon.
Kazumi Onee-chan.
Hey, you're here early.
Yeah, I just got here.
That shirt...
You used to wear it, right?
Yeah.
Aunty gave it to me a while ago.
Rin-chan, let me look at your teeth.
OK.
Now my two front teeth are starting to shake.
Are you all right? Does it hurt?
I'm fine. Sometimes it hurts,
but I'm already used to it.
I'm a pro.
Hey, Daikichi!
Can't you think of something! It's turned red!
It's only slightly red.
Speaking of which, didn't you ask me to tie a string and put it off when I was young?
String?
Oh my, something like that happened?
I'll try to make softer food.
Thanks!
Do you want some Koyadofu?
Koyadofu 高野豆腐 = Frozen dried tofu cubes
Sure.
Aunty, I can also eat simmered beans.
Yes yes!
Eat more of it.
I love Koyadofu.
It came off?
Rin-chan?
It dropped off!
Woah! Blood! Blood!
Mom! Tissues! tissues!
Wait! Wait!
I'm all right.
Rin, use this to hold it first.
That's a rag!
Rin-chan has changed a lot.
You think so?
Maybe this is the real Rin.
I heard you're getting married?
Mom told me about it just now.
Yeah.
Isn't that great. I heard he's a good person.
He's OK, I guess.
But that kind of person is the type that wants to have kids right away.
Now isn't that even better?
Who are you kidding!?
How do I go drinking? How do I go see live concerts?
Going on trips too, and eating good food.
I would end up not being able to do anything!
Talk to your future husband about things like that.
It won't change anything even if you talk to me.
Besides, I am not good with children.
I also don't want to turn into one of those thick-skinned old hags.
I don't have the confidence to sacrifice myself into looking after children.
No, I think there'll always be a way.
As long as you're willing.
It'll go well then even if you don't want it to.
You really love getting in other people's business, Onii-chan.
Yeah, perhaps.
What's with that?
I've never experienced being a mother.
I've also never experienced being a father or a husband.
It's burning.
It's true that I no longer have time to go shopping or have tea.
But the time when I work is my own time.
The time spent together with your child is also your own time.
They're precious.
I may be a parent myself, but I don't think I'm at all that different from others.
Besides, everyone around us has become a parent.
Yeah, I see.
That's right.
Kaga Family Grave
Grandpa, do you know?
My permanent teeth are already growing out.
Hey, Rin!
T-This is sweat!
Daikichi!
Hurry up!
Get ready!
Osu Elementary School Entrance Ceremony
That flower vase...
Masako-san also had it.
I'll be back very soon.
Daikichi!
What! Another one came off?
Mirror, mirror.
Perhaps, from now on,
I'll also get paranoid and anxious over the tiniest things.
But these people are the same.
Does it hurt?
Rin?
Look! Look! Daikichi!
What is this? Your face looks just like a kitten.
Doesn't it?
Let's mail it back home.
What? Send a photo of it over?
Nothing else matters.
Her smile.
It is what truly brings me joy.
Hurry, hurry!
All right.
Open your mouth.
Ah~!
I think this isn't too bad at all.
nichiyou no hare ta hirusagari
日曜の晴れた昼下がり
On a clear Sunday afternoon
kyou ha doko he yukou
今日はどこへ行こう
Where are we heading today?
kayoi nareta itsumono michi ga mabushiku kagayaite mieru
通いなれたいつもの道が　まぶしく輝いて見える
The usual road that we always take seems to be shining radiantly
terasu atatakai taiyou to tonari ni kimi ga ireba
照らすあたたかい太陽と　となりに君がいれば
The warm sun is shining with you still by my side
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
hashagidasu kimochi ni
はしゃぎだす気持ちに
While we're feeling so merry
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe ha doko made mo
声はどこまでも
Our voices are everywhere
mou High High High
もう　High　High　High
We're already high, high, high!
maiagaru kaze ni nori
まいあがる風にのり
Riding on the soaring wind
utae rairairai
歌えライライライ
Sing Rai, Rai, Rai!
koe mo tobi haneru
声も飛び跳ねる
Our voices are hopping too
Daikichi~!